Finding Aid for the Chancellor's Office Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume V June 26, 1900 - June 29, 1906 (Box 0374, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume VI June 29, 1906 - June 17, 1912 (Box 0374, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume VII June 17, 1912 - June 12, 1916 (Box 0374, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume VIII June 12, 1916 - June 6, 1921 (Box 0374, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume V August 31, 1894 - June 4, 1904 (Box 0375, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume VI June 13, 1904 - June 17, 1912 (Box 0375, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume VII-VIII June 17, 1912 - May 30, 1921 (Box 0375, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume IX June 6, 1921 - June 13, 1922 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume X June 28, 1922 - May 22, 1924 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XI June 9, 1924 - July 1, 1925 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XII July 1, 1925 - April 1, 1927 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XIII June 1, 1927 - June 11, 1928 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XIV June 11, 1928 - July 1929 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XV July 1, 1929 - June 10, 1931 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XVI June 11, 1931 - June 12, 1933 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XVII June 12, 1933 - November 20, 1934 (Box 0376, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XIX February 21, 1936 - June 7, 1937 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XVIII November 20, 1934 - February 21, 1936 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XX June 7, 1937 - June 7, 1938 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXI June 7, 1938 - June 13, 1939 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXII June 13, 1939 - June 10, 1940 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXIII June 10, 1940 - June 10, 1941 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXIV June 10, 1941 - June 5, 1942 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXV June 5, 1942 - March 17, 1943 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXVI March 17, 1943 - February 7, 1944 (Box 0377, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume I January 26, 1872 - May 13, 1880 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume II May 24, 1880 - February 25, 1884 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume III May 26, 1884 - August 8, 1888 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust -- Minutes Volume IV May 7, 1889 - June 19, 1894 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXIX February 1, 1946 - July 3, 1946 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXVII February 7, 1944 - February 5, 1945 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- Board of Trust Executive Committee -- Minutes Volume XXVIII February 5, 1945 - January 31, 1946 (Box 0378, Folder 0)
- "Fulfilling the Conception of a Grand University" 8/1-3/74 The Cloister, Sea Is., GA (7-22-74 Purdy) (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- "Fulfilling the Conception of a Grand University" 8/1-3/74, 2nd Printing The Cloister, Sea Island,GA (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- "Fulfilling the Conception of a Grand University" 8/1-3/74, 2nd Printing The Cloister, Sea Island,GA (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- "Fulfilling the Conception of a Grand University" 8/1-3/74, The Cloister, Sea Is.,GA Corrected Copy (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Academic Degrees Awarded in the Southern States 1963-64 (Southern Regional Education Board) (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Affirmative Action Plan, Vanderbilt University 1982 Volume I (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Affirmative Action Plan, Vanderbilt University 1982 Volume II (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Giving In America: Toward a Stronger Voluntary Sector Rpt Committee on Private Philanthropy and Pub. Needs (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Improving the Managerial Capability of Science and Technology in Brazil January 1974 - October 1978 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Joint University Libraries: A Study of Resources Needed And Their Estimated Cost, The 12-31-48 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Nashville Banner October 4, 1963 (Installation of Alexander Heard) (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Profile of V.U. 1956/76 Volume 1 (Descriptive) Prepared for the Ford Foundation 1966 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Profile of V.U. 1956/76 Volume 2 (Statistical) Prepared for the Ford Foundation 1966 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Proposal to Ford from Vanderbilt University June 1960 (#6 Branscomb) (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Proposal to Ford from Vanderbilt University June 1960 (#4 Branscomb) (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Report of the Commission to Review the Freshman Year -- Vanderbilt University April 1971 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- The College of Arts and Science -- Vanderbilt University (1971-72, 1972-73, 1973-78) November 1973 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Ties Which Should Exist October 1958 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Transition Plan Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 Vanderbilt University, The (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- University Goverance, Report of the Commission on October 1970 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- V.U.: Five Years, Ten Years, and Twenty Years hence by Harvie Branscomb 1960 Submitted to Ford Foundation (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- V.U.: Five Years, Ten Years, and Twenty Years hence by Harvie Branscomb 1960 Submitted to Ford Foundation, 196-1960 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- Vanderbilt University Centennial -- Program and Addresses October 3, 1975 (Box 0379, Folder 0)
- 5 Year Planning Study 1971-72: A Report of the Chanc. 3/71 Pt. 5 Oper. and Fiscal Planning, Alum. and Dev. (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- 5 Year Planning Study 1971-72: A Report of the Chancellor March 1971 Part 2 Undergraduate Schools (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- 5 Year Planning Study 1971-72: A Report of the Chancellor March 1971 Part 3 (The Graduate Schools) (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Joint University Libraries Study Committee Report June 6, 1978 (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 2 Executive Administration (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 3 School Programs, Summary and Priorities (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 4 Student Development Services (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 5 University Services (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Proposal for Science Development at Vanderbilt University 1965 (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- SGA Course Description -- Evaluation Booklet for 1977-78 (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Status of Campus Development April 1977 (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Status of Campus Development May 1, 1975 (5 copies) (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Vanderbilt Planning Study Abstracts -- Vanderbilt Planning Study 1964 (3 copies) (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Vanderbilt University Medical Center -- Planning Survey Spring 1960 (Box 0380, Folder 0)
- Serviing Southern Industry In Vanderbilt University 1929 (Box 0380, Folder 1)
- James Hampton Kirkland Memorial Booklet (2 copies) (Box 0380, Folder 2)
- Report of the Chancellor for the Academic Year 1951-52 (2 copies) (Box 0380, Folder 3)
- Report of the Chancellor for the Academic Year 1952-53 (Box 0380, Folder 4)
- Report of the Chancellor for the Academic Year 1953-54 (Box 0380, Folder 5)
- Report of the Chancellor for the Academic Year 1954-55 (2 copies) (Box 0380, Folder 6)
- Anglo Poverty in the Rural South (Center for the Study of Human Resources) April 1974 (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Beyond The Ballot: Organized Citizen Participation In Metropolitan Nashvlle (Urban Observatory) 1971 (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Human Resource Development in Rural Texas (Center for the Study of Human Resources) August 1973 (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 10 Law School (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 11 Divinity School (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 13 The Graduate School (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 14 School of Medicine (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 15 Special Studies (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 16 Conference on University Programs and Priorities (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 6, Part 1 Academic Services (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 6, Part 2 Academic Services (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 6, Part 3 Academic Services (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 7, Part 4 College of Arts and Science: Natural Sciences (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 7, Part 5 College of Arts and Science: Special Programs (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 8 School of Engineering (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume 9 School of Nursing (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Planning Profile 1973-74 Volume7, Part 3 College of Arts and Science: Social Science (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Political Education and Political Science: The National Center for Education in Politics, 1946-66 (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- The Second Hundred Years: A Study of the Develop. of V.U. in Metro. Davidson County 1-10-73 (2 copies) (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- Women At Vanderbilt: Report of the Chancellor's Commission on the Status of Women 8/76 (2 copies) (Box 0381, Folder 0)
- 10 Squared Years: A Story of the First Century of Vanderbilt University School of Engineering 1875-1975 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- A Nation Observed: Perspectives on America's World Role, Donald R. Lesh, Editor 1974 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- A Study of the Honor System at Vanderbilt University, Final Report of Faculty-Student Committee 1944 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- A Tribute to Governor Smith, Robert Moses 1962 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Agenda for Business and Higher Education, Business-Higher Education Forum, American Counc. on Education 1980 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Alumni Directory -- Vanderbilt Medical School 1972 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Appendices -- Racial Isolation in the Public Schools, U.S. Commission on Civil Rights 1967 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Conference On The Western Hemisphere: Issues For The 1970's April 29 - May 2, 1971 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Directory of Fellows 1925-74 -- John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation 1975 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Economic and Social Progress in Latin America: Annual Report 1973, Inter-American Development Bank (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Education for Employment: Knowledge for Action, Report of the Task Force on Education and Employ. Mar. 1979 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Emma Lazarus: Selections From Her Poetry And Prose, Morris U. Schappes, Editor 1967 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- For The Faculties: A Perspective On Vanderbilt's $55 Million Campaign November 1966 (2 copies) (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Increasing the Options: A Report of the Task Force on Southern Rural Development (March 1977) (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Leadership for Higher Education: The Campus View, Roger W. Heyns, Editor 1977 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Leadership Vitality: A Workbook for Academic Administrators by David G. Brown 1979 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Nashville: Its Character in a Changing America, Robert L. Mode, Editor 1981 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- On Leadership, International Business Machines Corporation, 1974 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Perspectives On Vanderbilt 1973-74 to 1977-78 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Pharmacology at Vanderbilt 1875-1975, B. V. Rama Sastry, 1978 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Regents External Degrees: College Proficiency Examinations (The University of the State of NY) 1973 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Reports of Griffenhagen and Associates for 1950 and 1953 and Dr. Thomas S. Reed for 1937 and 1947 (1962) (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Scientific and Educational Programs 1981-83, The Rockefeller University 1981 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Teh Soviet Union, Arms Control, and Disarmament: A Study of Soviet Attitudes, Alexander Dallin 1964 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- The College Presidency 1900-60: An Annotated Bibliography -- U.S. Dept Of Health, Education, and Welfare (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- The Economics of The Major Private Universities, William G. Bowen, Carnegie Committee on Higher Education 1968 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- The Frosh Annual 1965: An Introduction to the Class of 1969, Student Association, V.U. (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- The Present and the Future in Educational Technology, James D. Koerner, Alfred P. Sloan Found. 1976 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- The Right to Education and Access To Higher Education -- International Association Of Universities (Paris 1978) (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- Youth: Transition to Adulthood, Report of Panel on Youth of the President's Science Adivsory Committee 1972 (Box 0382, Folder 0)
- 5-Year Planning Study 1971-72: A Report to the Chancellor, 1971, Pt. 4 Academic and Student Support (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Proposal to the Ford Foundation from V.U., June 1960 (#7-Chancellor's Office File Copy) (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Report of Committee on Cooperation Between Peabody and V.U., June 10, 1936 (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Report of The Study of Closer Cooperation Between George Peabody College for Teachers and V.U., 1962 (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Staff Study No. 1: Utilization of Instructional Space at Geo. Peabody College and V.U., 1961 (3 copies) (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Staff Study No. 2: Analysis of Instruc. Progs. Fall Quar. or Sem., 1961, Peabody and V.U. (4 copies) (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Staff Study No. 3: Historical Analysis of Cooperation Between George Peabody and V.U., 1961 (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- The Story of the Joint University Libraries of Nashville, TN, A. Frederick Kuhlman, 1972 (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- Vanderbilt University: Five Years, Ten Years, and Twenty Years hence, Harvie Branscomb, 1960 (Box 0383, Folder 0)
- A Study of Vanderbilt University Hospital 1946 (4 copies) (Box 0384, Folder 0)
- New Goals and New Objectives: The Story of the $30 Million Program for Vanderbilt University, 0-0 (Box 0384, Folder 0)
- Plan of Metropolitan Government for Nashville and Davidson County, October 1956 (Box 0384, Folder 0)
- Rural Student Health Coalition: West Tennessee Project 1973, Meharry Medical College and V.U. (2 copies) (Box 0384, Folder 0)
- "Remarks of Chancellor Heard at Faculty Assembly 9-10-70" (Audiotape) (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- 2 wooden gavel stands, 0-0 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Alumni Giving Incentive Award 1977 from the U.S. Steel Foundation (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Award: Business Hall of Fame, Cornelius Vanderbilt 1979 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Box with light inside and inscription to Gertrude Conaway Vanderbilt from Board of Trust 1967 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Collection plate made of wood with attached note form Robt. A. McGaw 11-20-72 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Medal: Harold Sterling Vanderbilt July 6, 1964 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Plaque: From Nashville Education Improvement Project September 1, 1969 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Signatures of Board of Trust in appreciation of Gertrude Conaway Vanderbilt May 5, 1967 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Vanderbilt University flag, 0-0 (Box 0385, Folder 0)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Academy of Arts and Science (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Agnes Scott College (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Brown University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Case Western Reserve U. (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, College of Charleston (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Emory University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Hampden-Sydney College (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Harvard University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Indiana University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Iowa State University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Meharry Medical College (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Mercer College (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Michigan State University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Mississippi State University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Montevallo University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Princeton University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Southwestern University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Trinity University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Tusculum College (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Chicago (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Florida (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Houston System (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Kentucky (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Michigan (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Minnesota (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Mississippi (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Mississippi (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Missouri (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Nebraska (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Oregon (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Pennsylvania (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Rochester (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Texas (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Virginia (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Washington (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, University of Wisconsin (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Washington and Lee (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Washington University (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, William and Mary (Box 0007)
- Greetings to Chancellor Wyatt, Yale University (Box 0007)